Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
- SPEECHES, WRITINGS, AND TEACHING MATERIALS, 1927-1965; Series II; .75' (2 boxes)
  - The Craft of Musical Composition, Part III: 3-Part Writing, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Letter excerpts: 1940 Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker; Paul Hindemith-Gertrud Hindemith, Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker; 1941 Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker, Paul Hindemith-H. Fromm, Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker, Paul Hindemith-E. Voigt; 1942 Paul Hindemith-E. Voigt; 1945 Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker; 1946 Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker; 1966 Gertrud Hindemith-H. Boatwright re: publication; 1967 G. Lam-L. Noss; 1972 E. Richter-L. Noss; 1973 J. Dunlap-L. Noss
    - F. Lewin: errata list 1972
    - S. Slaten: review in The Musical Quarterly 1972
    - G. Nestler: review in Melos 1971 with photocopy of original German
    - C. Shackford: review in Journal of Music Theory 1972
    - Chapters 15-16 in English with autograph notes by Paul Hindemith
    - Chapter 17 translation by L. Noss in longhand
    - Translation of published Foreword
    - Chapter 19 on meter, published in A. Briner's biography
    - (see also Box 14/277-280, Microfilms Box 35)
  - Johann Sebastian Bach: ein verpflichtendes Erbe, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - I. Kemp: comments from his biography
    - Letter excerpt: Paul Hindemith-W. Strecker 1952
    - Publicity in Die Zeit 1951 for Hamburger Bachpreis
    - Publicity for Yale Press edition in Yale Alumni Magazine and New Haven Register 1952
    - Two autographed copies of German edition, two of American edition
  - A Composer's World - Horizons and Limitations, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Poster from Harvard University lectures 1949
    - Letter excerpts: 1950 Gertrud Hindemith-W. Strecker; 1956 Paul Hindemith-O. Cox; 1959 Gertrud Hindemith-O. Cox, Paul Hindemith-K. Bauer
    - W. Reich: review in Melos 1954 (photocopy in German)
    - Translation of introduction to Paul Hindemith's German version
  - Sterbende Gewässer, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Copy of original German address
    - L. Noss translation of same
  - Hindemith's Concept of an Ideal Music School, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - P. Cahn: article in Jahrbuch VI/77
  - On Mechanical Music/Zur mechanischen Musik, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - L. Noss: translation; initial publication in Deutsche Kammermusik, Baden-Baden (see Box 2, Folder 81 for complete program & articles)
  - Demands on Musical Amateurs, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - L. Noss: translation; initial publication in Musik und Gesellschaft
  - On the Viola d'amore (lecture in Cremona), 1937 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - L. Noss: translation; initial publication in Jahrbuch IV/74
  - Reflections on Today's Music (Cornell University lecture), 1940 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - G. Schubert: introduction, commentary, and translation into German, published in Festschrift Rudolf Stephan, Laaber 1990
  - Methods of Music Theory, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - A. Mendel: translation; initial publication in The Musical Quarterly
  - Die Berufung (from University of Zürich inaugural address), 1951 (Box 10, Folder 241)
    - Photocopy of excerpt, published in Neue Zeitschrift für Musik
  - In Rembrance of Wilhelm Furtwängler (memorial address), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 242)
    - L. Noss: translation; initial publication in Atlantis-Verlag: Wilhelm Furtwängler in the Judgment of his Time with photocopy from same
  - Hören und Verstehen ungewohnter Musik (University of Zürich lecture), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - Three copies of offprint from Jahrbuch III/73
    - 2 copies of J. Colman: translation of same
    - L. Noss: rough translation of same
  - Musical Life in the United States (notes for talk in Zürich), 1949 (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - L. Noss: translation
  - Das Vorspiel zum 'Tristan', 1965? (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Photocopy from Hundert Jahre Tristan, ed. W. Wagner
  - Response upon receiving the Balzan Prize in Rome, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Delivered in French; L. Noss: translation from German version, published in Paul Hindemith: Die letzten Jahre 1965
- COLLEGIUM MUSICUM, 1943-1960; Series III; 1' (2 boxes)
  The Collegium Musicum materials are housed in Boxes 11-12, with additional materials in oversize Box 43. Folders in Boxes 11-12 are arranged chronologically by performance. The materials include those performed at Yale University and in 1950 at Harvard University. Many of the scores from 1943 are holographs. Most of the scores after 1947 are in Paul Hindemith's hand, duplicated from holograph offset masters.
  - Generalities (Box 11, Folder 247)
    - Composite list of Yale singers and instrumentalists
    - H. Boatwright's lecture: Hindemith's Performance of Old Music, published in Jahrbuch III/73
    - Inventory of materials given to Collection by H. Boatwright, G. Lam, C. Miller; Library check copy of inventory
    - Correspondence between K. Stone, AMP and B. Schott's Söhne re: Yale Collegium series of publications
  - 26 April Concert, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - Announcement card
    - Programs without music sheet for rounds
    - Photocopy of review in New Haven Register, 27 April 1943
    - Paul Hindemith manuscript parts of Melchior Frank: Intrada XXI (Recorder I-II, Gamba I-II-III, Bass + Tutti, Gamba I and Gamba III)
    - Paul Hindemith manuscript of continuo realization for two harpsichords of Heinrich Schütz: Psalm 24
    - Paul Hindemith manuscript of G. Dufay: Mon cuer me fait (set of 4 instrumental parts)
    - Paul Hindemith manuscript of S. Scheidt: Courant à 5 ad imitationem (set of 5 instrumental parts)
  - Concert of French Music of the 13th and 14th Centuries, 14 May 1945 (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - Preliminary mimeographied program listing Yves Tinayre as soloist
    - 3 programs, each on single sheet
    - Mimeographed supplement with names of participants and text of sung portions - 3 copies
    - List of expenses from C. Miller
    - Paul Hindemith letter to participants thanking them
    - Performance materials, mostly bass parts copied by C. Miller
    - Voice parts for composite Mass - soprano, alto, tenor
    - Paul Hindemith unsigned draft of letter to participants of concert
  - Concert of 14th & 15th Century Music, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - 3 copies of program and 1 complimentary ticket
    - 2 copies of press release
    - H. Blume: review in The Gazette Montreal, 15 June 1945
    - New Haven Register review, 21 May 1946
    - R. Morin: notice in Worcester Telegram/Evening Gazette in advance of concert
    - Expense sheets for costs, shipping notices to and from Metropolitan Museum of Art
    - Letters from E. Winternitz/Metropolitan Museum of Art to C. Miller with answers; H. Leichtentritt, et al
  - 14th & 15th Century - music folder, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - Audience sheets: Se la face ay pale - unaccompanied song; Dufay: Gloria ad modum tubae, canon; Wolkenstein: Good Host..., Unfold, unfold..., two canons
    - Dunstable: Veni Sancte Spiritus (4-part open score)
    - Mouton: L'homme armé (4-part instruments)
    - Dufay: Se la face ay pale (soprano & 2 instruments, also for 4-parts; upper part is bowed); holograph of separate Rebec part
    - Dufay: Missa se la face ay pale - Kyrie, Gloria (ad modum tubae), Credo, Sanctus, Agnus Dei, Dona nobis pacem
    - Isorhythmic Motet: Regina Saeculi-Reparatrix Maria
    - Binchois: Inter natos mulierum (3-part open score)
    - Grenon: La plus jolie (3-part open score)
    - Binchois: J'ay tant de deul (soprano & 2 instruments open score); holograph of separate Rebec part
    - Binchois: Je loe amours (soprano & 2 instruments open score); holograph of separate Rebec part
    - Hayne: Penser en vous (soprano & 2 instruments open score); holograph of separate Rebec part
    - von Wolkenstein: Frölich geschrai, wo well wir machen (soprano & 2 instruments open score)
    - Binchois: A solis ortu cardine (3-part open score)
    - Anon.: Terriblement suis fortunée (3-part open score)
    - Zaccaria: Cacciando per gustar di quel tesoro (3-part open score)
    - Monophonic Dances: La ultime estampie real; La seconde estampie royal
    - Rebec parts to Dance, La Manfredina, Estampie royale, Tre Fontane, Trotto, Saltarello
    - Holographs of Tromba marina parts for Dance, Estampie royale, Tre Fontane
    - Music eliminated from program - Arnoldus de Lantins: Tota pulchra es (3-part voices instrument); Binchois: Filles à marier (2-part voices & 2 instruments)
  - Music of the Fifteenth Century, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - Programs
    - Letters: C. Sachs, A. Quimby, D. Plamenac, C. Champagne, F. Sternfeld, O. Strunk, W. Apel, G. Reese, W. Woodruff, E. Winternitz, E. Weissmann, A. Mendel, O. Kinkeldey, M. deFores Payne, S. Beck, C. Guarnieri
    - Expense Accounts
    - Ticket, postcard from American Musicological Society, sample of letter-announcement, publicity release
    - Review: New Haven Register, 24 March 1947
    - Holograph notes to T41 History of Theory choral group, written late in 1946 in advance of 23 March 1947 concert
  - Music of the Fifteenth Century - music folder, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 253)
    - Audience sheet of four canons: Exsultate, iusti; Dolorum solacium; de Orto: Exsultate, justi; Anon. Dolorum solacium
    - Compère: Missa l'homme armé - Kyrie
    - Finck: Missa in summis - Credo
    - Flordigal: Cui luna, sol et omnia (4-part open score)
    - Agricola: D'ung aultre amer (4-part open score)
    - Stockem: Brunette
    - Obrecht: Missa sub tuum praesidium confugimus - Sanctus and Benedictus
    - Tinctoris: Missa cunctorum plasmator - Agnus Dei
    - von Fulda: In decollatione S. Johannis Baptistae - Nuntius, celso
    - Anon.: Ich sachs eins mals (soprano & 2 instruments open score)
    - Anon.: In feuers hitz (soprano & 3 instruments open score)
    - Ockeghem: Ma bouche rit (soprano & 2 instruments open score)
    - de la Torre: Airado va el gentil hombre (soprano 3 instruments open score)
    - Medina: No hay placer (soprano & 3 instruments open score)
    - Anon.: Noch weet ic een ionc vraukin fijn (3-part open score)
    - Phillips: I love, I love, and whom love ye? (3-part open score)
    - Cornish: Jolly Rutterkin (3-part open score)
    - Barbireau: Der Pfobenschwancz (4-part open score)
    - Rubinus: Der Bauernschwanz (4-part open score)
    - Obrecht: Ic draghe de mutse clutse (3-part open score)
    - Anon.: Hor oires une chanson - holograph of Viola I part
    - Obrecht: Tsat een meskin - holograph of Viola I part
    - Okeghem: Missa caput - Gloria unused
    - Preliminary program
    - Instrumentation sheet, manuscript Howard Boatwright
  - Music of the Early 16th Century, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 254)
    - Programs
    - Letters: B. Colton, G. P. Smith
    - Review: photocopy from New Haven Register, 21 May 1948
    - Printing orders to Chinese Printing Office for copies of various sung works, concert announcements, letterheads
    - Account records of expenditures
    - Correspondence re: borrowing of instruments from Metropolitan Museum of Art and arrangements for repeat of concert there
    - Personnel list for program
  - Early 16th Century - music folder, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    (see also holograph masters for Chinese Printing Office in oversize Box 43)
    - Composite Mass with Gregorian proper for Pentecost:
    - Pierre de la Rue: Kyrie
    - Senfl: Missa paschalis - Gloria
    - Isaac: Missa de assumptione beata Marie virginie - Credo
    - Mouton: Missa alma redemptoris - Sanctus
    - LTosquin: Missa l'homme armé sexti toni - Agnus Dei
    - Josquin: Misere mei Deus
    - von Bruck: Ich stund an einem Morgen (6-part open score)
    - Greiter: Ich stund... (tenor & 3 instruments open score)
    - Isaac: Ich stund ... (4-part open score)
    - Senfl: Ich stund ... (4-part open score)
    - Senfl: Ich stund ... (tenor & 5 instruments open score)
    - Finck: Ich stund ... (4-part open score)
    - Senfl: Entlaubet ist der Walde (4-part open score)
    - Heugel: Entlaubet... (tenor & 3 instruments open score - 2 versions)
    - Senfl: Entlaubet... (sopranos & tenor in canon with 2 instruments open score)
    - Stolzer: Entlaubet... (4-part open score)
    - Senfl: Zwischen Berg und tiefem Tal (tenor & 3 instruments open score)
    - Isaac: Zwischen Berg... (4-part open score)
    - Finck: Greiner, Zanner (open score)
    - Hofhaimer: Greiner, Zanner (3-part open score)
    - Isaac: Greiner, Zanner (4-part open score)
    - du Tertre: Pavan avec Gaillarde (5-part open score)
    - Anon.: Tourdion, C'est grand plaisir; Bransle simple (4-part open score)
    - Gervaise: Bransle de Bourgonge; Bransle simple (4-part open score)
    - du Tertre: Bransle d'Escosse; Pavan (4-part open score)
    - Lemlin: Der Gutzgauch auf dem Zaune sass (4-part open score with 2-part cuckoo); holograph of Viola I part
    - Jannequin: Le chant des oiseaux (4-part open score)
    - Song for the Audience with text by Richard Edwardes
    - Preliminary program for rehearsals with designations for small/large chorus, tenor solo, specific instruments
    - Isaac: La mi la sol - holograph of soprano-alto-bass parts unused
  - Commemoratio brevis - Collegium newsletter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - 21 Feb, 28 Feb, 6 Mar, 13 Mar, 20 Mar, 27 Mar (with Easter greetings from Paul Hindemith and drawing), 17 Apr, 24 Apr, 1 May, 15 May, 3 June (a message from Paul Hindemith)
  - Harvard Concerts, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 257)
    - Harvard-Radcliffe Glee Club program 16-17 March comprising Schutz: St. John Passion, two Bach chorales, Canon for, Mrs. Coolidge, Paul Hindemith's Frau Musica
    - 1950 March: Collegium Program cut from Harvard University Gazette 27 + complete program booklet
    - Tournai Mass: Kyrie
    - Guillaume de Machaut: Gloria
    - Anon. early 15th century: Missa o rosa bella - Credo (3-part open score) unused
    - Guillaume Dufay: Agnus Dei
    - von Wolkenstein: Frölleich geschrai so well wir machen - krummhorn part (3-part open score)
    - Holograph of krummhorn part for Medieval Dances + note from H. Brown
    - Piero di Firenze (14th cent. ): Con bracchi assai (3-part open score) + note from H. Brown
    - Two notes from H. Brown
    - Holograph masters of Perotin: Sederunt principes; Kyrie from Tournai Mass; Machaut: Gloria
  - Music of the Sixteenth Century, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 258)
    - Programs of 21 May at Yale; repeated at Cloisters of Metropolitan Museum, 5 June, 1951
    - Expense accounting, publicity release, sample ticket, statements for ads, shipping costs from Metropolitan Museum, Chinese Printing Office costs for reproduction of music
  - Music of the Sixteenth Century - music folder, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 259)
    - Gregorian Introit
    - Byrd: Kyrie (5-part open score)
    - de Monte: Missa cum sit omnipotens rector Olympi - Gloria (6-part open score)
    - Gregorian Gradual & Alleluia
    - Palestrina: Missa sine nomine - Credo (6-part open score)
    - Gregorian Offertory
    - A. Gabrieli: Sanctus (3 4-part choirs open score)
    - J. Handl: Missa Elisabethae impletum est tempus - Agnus Dei
    - J. Handl: Mirabile mysterium (5-part open score)
    - Gesualdo: Itene ò miei sospiri (5-part open score)
    - No copies of Byrd 5-part and 6-part Fantasias
    - di Lasso: Ogni occhio, from Lagrime di San Pietro (6-part open score)
    - le Jeune: L'aspre fureur (4-part open score)
    - di Lasso: Im lant zu Wirtenberg (4-part open score)
    - A. Gabrieli: Alla battaglia, Part 1 of I. and Part 2 of II. - no instrumental parts; 6-part open score; with Chinese Printing Office masters
    - Paul Hindemith: Alla battaglia, a canon for audience with English text
  - Commemoratio brevis, 1951, undated (Box 12, Folder 260)
    - Battaglia
    - Handel & Vicentino
    - Palestrina
    - Gesualdo
    - Villanelle
    - Byrd: Fantasies
    - Crossword puzzle
    - Byrd; translations of Lasso madrigal
    - Lasso
    - A. Gabrieli
    - Philippe de Monte
    - The Renaissance Artist in Relation to his Society
  - Concert, 14 May 1953 (Box 12, Folder 261)
    - Programs with change of program sheet + repeat performance at Metropolitan Museum of Art
    - Various bills relating to costs of printing, honoraria, recordings, seating chart, etc.
    - Photo from New Haven Register, 26 April 1953
    - J. Harrison: review of New York performance in New York Herald Tribune
    - Mailer/flyer
    - Dress Rehearsal program with notes by Mason Martens
  - 14 May Concert - music folder, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - Pérotin: Alleluia. Nativitas gloriosae (3-part open score)
    - Dufay: Missa ave Regina caelorum - Kyrie
    - Glogauer Liederbuch: Seh in mein Herz - MISSING
    - Glogauer Liederbuch: Früntlich begir senet sich nach dir
    - Glogauer Liederbuch: Zu aller Zeit
    - Glogauer Liederbuch: Mein schönstes Lib auf Erden
    - Glogauer Liederbuch: Ich beins erfreut
    - Monteverdi: Sestina, Lagrime d'Amate al Sepolcro dell'Amata
    - Weelkes: O care thou wilt despatch me (5-part open score)
    - Weelkes: A Sparrow Hawk proud (6-part open score)
    - G. Gabrieli: Four pieces from Sacrae Symphoniae -MISSING; holograph of parts to I. Cantus of Sonata octavi toni & Canzon quarti toni
    - Galilei: Contrappunto a dui Liuti - MISSING
    - Gesualdo: Dolcissima mia vita (5-part open score)
    - Gesualdo: Io pur respiro
    - J. S. Bach: Singet dem Herrn ein neues Lied (2 4-part choirs) Möseler edition
  - Commemoratio Brevis, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 263)
    - no. 1, 3 Feb 1953
    - no. 2, 10 Feb 1953
    - no. 3, 17 Feb 1953
    - no. 4, 24 Feb 1953
    - no. 5 ?
    - no. 6 [missing]
    - no. 7, 14 Apr 1953
    - no. 8, 21 Apr 1953
    - no. 9, 18 Apr 1953
    - no. 10, 5 May 1953
  - 19 February Concert, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 264)
    - Programs with Paul Hindemith's Madrigal texts inserted
    - Ad proof, advance notices from Yale Daily News, New York Times
    - Reviews: G. E. A. in New Haven Register 20 Feb; F. R. J. in New Haven Journal Courier
    - Press releases
    - Various letters re: obtaining music from Boosey & Hawkes, Schott, AMP, etc. plus letters of appreciation
    - Paul Hindemith autographed copy of G. Gabrieli's Omnes gentes plaudite
  - Other Concerts & Lectures, 1938-1958 (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - 27 February 1938 in Jonathan Edwards College, autographed
    - 24 February 1942 in Sprague Hall - H. I. F. Biber: Eight Biblical Sonatas, with R. Kirkpatrick, M. Kirshbaum, G. Lam
    - 17 October 1943 - notice of American Guild of Organists meeting with lecture by Paul Hindemith
    - 23-24 November 1945 - three concerts at Juilliard in honor of Paul Hindemith's 50th birthday
    - 12 March 1951 - Fifth Annual Symposium of International Federation of Music Students. Paul Hindemith gave opening lecture: Musical Imagination
    - 30 November/4 December 1958 - Beethoven Festival
- ADDITIONAL CONCERTS AND COURSE MATERIALS, 1938-1985; Series IV; 1' (2 boxes)
  During the weekend of 7-8 November 1964, the year following the composer's death, the Yale School of Music held a celebration commemorating Paul Hindemith at Yale. This event included three concerts and an exhibition in Beinecke Library of scores, letters, drawings, student projects, concert programs, and other memorabilia. Records of this commemoration, including photographs, are contained in Box 13.
  Also contained in this series are copies of special examinations Paul Hindemith prepared for entering students, projects the composer completed in class, student projects, degree requirements, class notes, and materials related to his teaching of theory, composition, the history of theory, and his musicianship training program.
  Complete lists of students enrolled in his classes, lists of composition and theory majors, and programs of composition students are also contained in Box 13.
  Preceding Parts III and IV of "The Craft of Musical Composition" are files containing materials from other Hindemith festivals held at Yale University, Eugene, Oregon, Ohio State University, The University of Kentucky, and various cities in Germany (Box 13).
  - Yale Commemoration, 7-8 November 1964 (Box 13, Folder 266)
    - Press releases
    - Dee Bair: full page & a half article in New Haven Register 1 Nov with many pictures
    - G. Armstrong: review in New Haven Register 8 November
    - R. Ericson: advance notice in New York Times 1 November
    - Yale Alumni Magazine, December 1964 - 6 pages devoted to commemoration plus two and a half columns in The Editor's Window
    - Yale School of Music Alumni Newsletter article
  - Yale Commemoration - exhibit data, requests, correspondence, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 267)
    (see oversize Box 43 for original poster)
    - Labels from the exhibit
    - George Lam: "Thank You" in Latin
    - Exhibit inventory
    - Statements from Printing Office
    - L. Noss: opening remarks
    - Letters: G. Lam-J. Iadone, -C. Miller, -R. Gottlieb, -G. Samuel, -M. Selden, B. Shepard-R. Donovan, -E. Grumman, -A. Planchart
  - Yale Commemoration - programs, attendance data, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - Invitations, schedules
    - Paul Hindemith at Yale 1940-1953 general programs
    - Paul Hindemith: Alla battaglia, reprinted from concert, sung by all guests at dinner in President's Room, 21 May 1951
    - 7 November program in Jonathan Edwards College
    - 8 November program of Mass in St. Thomas More chapel
    - 8 November program of choral & orchestral music in Woolsey Hall
    - List of friends and associates
    - List of former students
    - Mailing list of former students September 1964
  - 15-16 February Concerts, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Announcement
    - Ads & G. Emerson: advance article in New Haven Register 4 February
    - Poster
    - 15 Feb program - Ludus Tonalis
    - 16 Feb program 4 pm - chamber music
    - 16 Feb program 8:30 pm - orchestral & choral music
    - Letter: K. Wilson-L. Noss
    - Letter: B. Stern-L. Noss
    - Letter: L. Noss-C. Coss
    - Letter: T. Holt-L. Noss
    - Letter: M. Martens-L. Noss
    - Letter: G. Hunter-L. Noss
    - Letter: D. Kraehenbuehl-L. Noss
    - Letter: C. Miller-L. Noss
    - Letter: C. Shackford-L. Noss
    - Telegram: Volk-L. Noss (German)
  - Various Student Lists (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - Theory majors, Composition majors, Theory & composition majors, others who took courses; still others who were special students
    - 1984 mailing list with addresses
    - Photocopies of catalogues with degrees conferred
  - Class Lists (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - 1940-41
    - 1941-42
    - 1942-43
    - 1943-44
    - 1944-45
    - 1945-46
    - 1946-47
    - 1947-48
    - 1948-49
    - 1950-51 + work sheet
    - 1952-53
  - Materials Prepared by Paul Hindemith for Courses, Exams, etc. (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - (Additional materials prepared by Paul Hindemith for class use and completed student projects are in Boxes 24-28, with some items on microfilm - Box 34.)
    - 1940s early: Entrance exam in Musicianship, Paul Hindemith autograph
    - 1940 Spring: Paul Hindemith illustration of polytonality which was written on board during lecture
    - 1942 September: exam in course H-44b - 4 questions
    - 1946: Entrance exam for composition majors
    - 1947 September: entrance exam for composition majors; solution by H. Laudenslager
    - 1948 June 3: Final exam; solutions by C. Miller, V. Archer
    - 1950 September: comments on entrance tests and interviews of applicants for admission to Yale University School of Music
    - 1952: Plan for lst movement of a symphony - from Zurich seminar
    - Student composition programs: 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945?, 1946, 1948, 1949, 1953
    - Class reports to Department of Music on undergraduates in Paul Hindemith's courses
  - FESTIVALS OUTSIDE YALE
    - Eugene, Oregon Festivals, 1981, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 273)
      - Programs: 1981, 1982, 1983
      - Photocopy J. D. McAlister: review in Eugene Register-Guard, 18 June 1981